<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Way of the Mountain's Eye</name>
		<description>The Way of the Mountain's Eye from Paddy's Homebrew</description>
		<author>Paddy's Homebrew</author>
		<update version="0.0.3">
			<file name="monk-mountain.xml" url="https://github.com/PaddyBergin/Homebrew/blob/master/PaddyB/monk-mountain.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Way of the Mountain's Eye" type="Archetype" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_MONK_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE">
		<supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A monk who follows the Way of the Mountain's Eye believes their body is an illusion. They see their ki as a representation of their true form, an astral self. This astral self has the capacity to be a force of order or disorder, with some monasteries training students to use their power to protect the weak and other instructing aspirants in how to manifest their true selves in service to the mighty.</p>
			<div element="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_EXPLOIT_WEAKNESS" />
			<div element="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_DEBILITATING_TOUCH" />
			<div element="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_CEREBRAL_STRIKES" />
			<div element="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_UNSTOPPABLE_FORCE" />
			<div element="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_INFLICT_MADNESS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_EXPLOIT_WEAKNESS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_DEBILITATING_TOUCH" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_CEREBRAL_STRIKES" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_UNSTOPPABLE_FORCE" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_INFLICT_MADNESS" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Exploit Weakness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_EXPLOIT_WEAKNESS">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level Way of the Mountain's Eye feature</em></p>
			<p>Your keen understanding of the structure of buildings and creatures allows you to identify the cracks and wounds, even of those that have long since faded.</p>
			<p>Beginning at 3rd level you can use your bonus action to examine a creature or structures weaknesses.</p>
			<p>Once per turn, when striking a creature or structure you have examined, it recieves the following effects when succesfully attacked</p>
			<p class="indent">If your target is a living creature, upon a successful attack you can spend 1 Ki point to remove its resistance to all types of damage until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">If your target is a structure, you deal the maximum damage to it.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>Beginning at 3rd level you can use your bonus action to examine a creature or structure. 
			If the target is a structure you deal the maximum amount of damage to it. If the target is a living creature, 
			upon a successful attack you can remove its resistance to damage until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Debilitating Touch" type="Archetype Feature" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_DEBILITATING_TOUCH">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level Way of the Mountain's Eye feature</em></p>
			<p>Your very strike crumbles the enemies resolve, both for their mind and their body.</p>
			<p>Beginning at third level on a successful attack, you can spend a ki point to give the target disadvantage on either wisdom or constitution saving throws until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Beginning at third level on a successful attack, you can spend a ki point to give the target disadvantage on a saving throw of your choice until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Cerebral Strikes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_CEREBRAL_STRIKES">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level Way of the Mountain's Eye feature</em></p>
			<p>Your fists no longer just deal damage to your opponents body, each strike you make inflicts damage on your enemies mind. Your unarmed strikes deal psychic damage.</p>
			<p>Additionally, any critical hit made with unarmed strikes causes your opponent to become afraid of you until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your fists no longer just deal damage to your opponents body, each strike you make inflicts damage on your enemies mind. Your unarmed strikes deal psychic damage. 
			
			Additionally, any critical hit made with unarmed strikes cause your opponent to become afraid of you until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Unstoppable force" type="Archetype Feature" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_UNSTOPPABLE_FORCE">
		<description>
			<p><em>11th-level Way of the Mountain's Eye feature</em></p>
			<p>Channelling your mountainous integrity makes you an unchallengable force of movement</p>
			<p>Starting at 11th level you can spend 1 ki point and use your action to momentarily becomes an unstoppable force. You can move up to half of your movement speed dealing damage to anything you make contact with.</p>
			<p>Any creature or structure you come within 5ft of during this movement takes a number of d8 equivalent to your dex modifier. Any creature you come into contact with must make a strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>you can use your action to momentarily become an unstoppable force. By spending a ki point you can travel half your normal speed dealing damage to anything you make content with. 
			This attack deals {{wisdom:modifier}}d8 bludgeoning damage once to each creature or structure that you come within 5ft of until the end of this movement.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Inflict Madness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_INFLICT_MADNESS">
		<description>
			<p><em>17th-level Way of the Mountain's Eye feature</em></p>
			<p>The body and mind are interconnected, and your comprehension of this link allows you to strike with the intent of damaging both mind and body simultaneously.</p>
			<p>At level 17 when you hit a creature with unnamed strike, you can expend 3 ki points to paralyse them, after the paralysis ends they are frightened of you for the next 10 minutes.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>At level 17 when you hit a creature with unnamed strike, you can expend 3 ki points to paralyse them, after the paralysis ends they are frightened of you for the next 10 minutes.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
  
</elements>
