<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Way of the Mountain's Eye</name>
		<description>The Way of the Mountain's Eye from Paddy's Homebrew</description>
		<author>Paddy's Homebrew</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="monk-mountain.xml" url="https://github.com/PaddyBergin/Homebrew/blob/master/PaddyB/archetypes/monk-mountain.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Way of the Mountain's Eye" type="Archetype" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_MONK_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE">
		<supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A monk who follows the Way of the Mountain's Eye believes their body is an illusion. They see their ki as a representation of their true form, an astral self. This astral self has the capacity to be a force of order or disorder, with some monasteries training students to use their power to protect the weak and other instructing aspirants in how to manifest their true selves in service to the mighty.</p>
			<div element="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_EXPLOIT_WEAKNESS" />
			<div element="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_DEBILITATING_TOUCH" />
			<div element="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_CEREBRAL_STRIKES" />
			<div element="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_UNSTOPPABLE_FORCE" />
			<div element="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_AWAKENED_ASTRAL_SELF" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_EXPLOIT_WEAKNESS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_DEBILITATING_TOUCH" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_CEREBRAL_STRIKES" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_UNSTOPPABLE_FORCE" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_AWAKENED_ASTRAL_SELF" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Exploit Weakness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_EXPLOIT_WEAKNESS">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level Way of the Mountain's Eye feature</em></p>
			<p>Your keen understanding of the structure of buildings and creatures allows you to identify the cracks and wounds, even of those that have long since faded.</p>
			<p class="indent">Beginning at 3rd level you can use your bonus action to examine a creature or structure. If the target is a structure you deal the maximum amount of damage to it.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the target is a living creature, upon a successful attack you can remove its resistance to damage until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>Beginning at 3rd level you can use your bonus action to examine a creature or structure. 
			If the target is a structure you deal the maximum amount of damage to it. If the target is a living creature, 
			upon a successful attack you can remove its resistance to damage until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Debilitating Touch" type="Archetype Feature" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_EXPLOIT_WEAKNESS">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level Way of the Mountain's Eye feature</em></p>
			<p>Your very strike crumbles the enemies resolve.</p>
			<p>Beginning at third level on a successful attack, 
			you can spend a ki point to give the target disadvantage on wisdom and constitution 
			saving throws until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Beginning at third level on a successful attack, you can spend a ki point to give the target disadvantage on a saving throw of your choice until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Cerebral strikes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_CEREBRAL_STRIKES">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level Way of the Mountain's Eye feature</em></p>
			<p>Your fists no longer just deal damage to your opponents body, each strike you make inflicts damage on your enemies mind. Your unarmed strikes deal psychic damage.</p>
			<p>Additionally, any critical hit made with unarmed strikes causes your opponent to become afraid of you until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your fists no longer just deal damage to your opponents body, each strike you make inflicts damage on your enemies mind. Your strikes with any weapon deal psychic damage. 
			
			Additionally, any critical hit made with unarmed strikes cause your opponent to become afraid of you until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Unstoppable force" type="Archetype Feature" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_UNSTOPPABLE_FORCE">
		<description>
			<p><em>11th-level Way of the Mountain's Eye feature</em></p>
			<p>Channelling your mountainous integrity makes you an unchallengable force of movement</p>
			<p>Starting at 11th level you can spend 1 ki point and use your action to momentarily becomes an unstoppable force. You can move up to half of your movement speed dealing damage to anything you make contact with.</p>
			<p>Any creature or structure you come within 5ft of during this movement takes a number of d8 equivalent to your dex modifier. Any creature you come into contact with must make a strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you have both your astral arms and visage summoned, you can cause the body of your astral self to appear. This spectral body covers your physical form like a suit of armor, connecting with the arms and visage. You determine its appearance. 
			While the spectral body is present, you gain the following benefits: &#13;
			Deflect Energy. When you take acid, cold, fire, force, lightning, or thunder damage, you can use your reaction to deflect it. When you do so, the damage you take is reduced by 1d10 + {{body of the astral self:deflect damage}}. &#13;
			Empowered Arms. Once on each of your turns when you hit a target with the Arms of the Astral Self, you can deal extra 1d{{martial arts:dice}} damage to the target.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="body of the astral self:deflect damage" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="body of the astral self:deflect damage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Awakened Astral Self" type="Archetype Feature" source="Paddy's Homebrew" id="ID_PBERGIN_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_MOUNTAINS_EYE_AWAKENED_ASTRAL_SELF">
		<description>
			<p><em>17th-level Way of the Mountain's Eye feature</em></p>
			<p>Your connection to your astral self is complete, allowing you to unleash its full potential. As a bonus action, you can spend 5 ki points to summon the arms, visage, adn body of your astral self and awaken it for 10 minutes. This awakening ends early if you are incapacitated or die.</p>
			<p class="indent">While your astral self is awakened, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Armor of the Spirit.</em></strong> You gain a +2 bonus to Armor Class.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Astral Barrage.</em></strong> Whenever you use the Extra Attack feature to attack twice, you can instead attack three times if all the attacks are made with your astral arms.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You can spend 5 ki points to summon the arms, visage, adn body of your astral self and awaken it for 10 minutes. This awakening ends early if you are incapacitated or die. 
			While your astral self is awakened, you gain the following benefits: &#13;
			Armor of the Spirit. You gain a +2 bonus to Armor Class. &#13;
			Astral Barrage. Whenever you use the Extra Attack feature to attack twice, you can instead attack three times if all the attacks are made with your astral arms.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
  
</elements>
